{
    "id": "db5ddc02b04940408e2b9a052bf7702b",
    "title": "If Clauses",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "5a66182f09aa42f996ed991acd177c3a",
            "title": "If-Clauses Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "If you ………………………… respect, you get respect.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "give",
                        "will give",
                        "would give"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If she studies well, she …………………………. good marks.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "will get",
                        "gets",
                        "would get"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ……………………………. to earn more money, you have to work harder.",
                    "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "want",
                        "wanted",
                        "had wanted"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ………………………….. him, tell him that I am waiting for him.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "meet",
                        "met",
                        "had met"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you ………………………….. out, you will not lose that belly fat.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "don't work",
                        "didn't work",
                        "hadn't worked"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I ……………………….. more money, I could buy a car.",
                    "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "have",
                        "had",
                        "had had"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If it rains, we …………………………….. get wet.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "will",
                        "would",
                        "could"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "If I …………………………. you, I would not tolerate this.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "am",
                        "were",
                        "had been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Had I seen the signal, I …………………………...",
                    "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
                    "answers": [
                        "will stop",
                        "would stop",
                        "would have stopped"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If you had told me you were not coming, I ……………………………… waited for you.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "won't have",
                        "wouldn't have",
                        "couldn't have"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "If they had found him early, he …………………………….. saved.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "will be",
                        "would be",
                        "would have been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "If she hadn’t married him, she …………………………….. happy.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "will be",
                        "would be",
                        "would have been"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}